dvla-som.co.uk 2017-06-27

# Privacy

  * SUPER SEARCH
  * PREFIX SEARCH
  * CURRENT SEARCH
  * NI REGISTRATIONS

These registrations are dateless and can be assigned to any appropriate vehicle registered within mainland Great Britain and Northern Ireland. Please click View for a selection of Northern Ireland (NI) registrations that can be purchased for a fixed price.

View

This page explains our privacy policy and how we will use and protect any information about you that you give us when you visit this website.

* * *

## The Data Protection Act

This page explains our privacy policy and how we will use and protect any information about you that you give us when you visit this website.

* * *

## What information do we collect?

Under the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it.

* * *

## Feedback

We welcome your feedback.

Should you send an email to us seeking advice or information that we are not in a position to give, we may forward your email on to a more appropriate department within the government for a response. If we do this we will send you an email informing you of our actions.

Once we have replied to you, we keep a record of your message for a maximum of two months for reference and audit purposes, after which we will delete it.

* * *

## Site usage information

### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of data that are often created when you visit a website, and which are stored in the cookies directory of your computer. Cookies are created when you visit dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk.

Our cookies store a random number and other information such as a date on your computer to help us count the number of times users return to our site.

The cookies do not contain any personal information about you, and they cannot be used to identify an individual user.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies. If you do not know how to do this, contact us, giving details on the type of browser you are using, and we will do our best to help. However some features of the site may not work as expected if all cookies are disabled.

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally. 

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through "[Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them](https://www.gov.uk/help/cookies)

### Our use of cookies

The cookies used on our Personalised Registrations website: 

Cookies stored by Google analytics used to provide DVLA with website analysis. 

Current session ID used to link the current user session to actions performed on the website for functionality and statistics (including the return from the purchasing process to confirm a sale). 

Last session ID used to determine when a visitor last visited (if present) for statistics. 

Last visit date/time used to record the date and time the user last visited for statistical purposes. 

Wishlist ID used to store a link to databases of wishlist number plates for keeping the user's saved plates.are when a user is taking advantage of our wish list facility that keeps a memory of certain registration numbers identified by the user.

### Page tagging

We use JavaScript to aggregate and analyse customer usage patterns on the dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk domain. This provides us with data on your usability and behaviour. We use this information to make changes to the layout of the website and to the information in it. This does not collect any personal or identifiable information about users.

We sometimes tag pages on this website during promotion campaigns. These tags enable us to find out which advertisements are successful in bringing users to our internet site(s). With this technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable.

You can disable JavaScript on your computer. If you would like advice on how to disable JavaScript please contact us, giving details about the type of browser you use and we will do our best to help. Disabling JavaScript may affect your ability to access certain features on the website.

### What happens when I link to another site?

dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk contains links to other websites, both of government departments and of other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement of any other site(s) which collect personal information about you.

We do not pass on any personal information you have given us to any other site.

What happens when I access the dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk site through another site?

Where you are directed to the dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk site from another site (whether a third party site or a government site) we may receive personal information relating to you from the other site(s). You should read the privacy policies applicable to such sites as these will govern the use of any personal information that you provide when accessing such sites and which is provided to dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk.

### Security

When accessing the 'my account' and purchasing sections of the website all information you send and receive is transferred thought a Secure Socker Layer connection (SSL). SSL creates a secure link between your browser and our server. We use SSL with 128-bit encryption which is widely accepted as the industry standard.

SSL encrypts your personal information before it leaves your computer and guarantees that it is not altered between your computer and our server and unauthorised users cannot read it.

### Access to your information and contacting dvlaregistrations.direct.gov.uk

If you wish to see our records of any correspondence you have sent to us, or if you have a query or complaint about this privacy policy or about the site, you can contact us by email.

### Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
